

REEGUN RUFUS G

Software Engineer



My Contact

reegunrufus07@gmail.com

+916379435342, 9047125185

No 2, LIG Colony, Mount Pleasant, Coonoor, Tamil Nadu, 643102.

Areas of Expertise

- Technical Strengths: Artificial Intelligence, AWS, Database, Flutter, Data Structures, AngularJs, Spring Boot, Linux, Multi-Threading, SDLC.
- Programming Languages: Python, C, C++, Java, C#, Dart, SQL.
- Languages: English (Fluent), Tamil (Native), Hindi (Intermediate).
- Soft Skills: Observation, Decision Making, Communication, Multi-Tasking, Leadership.

Education Background

 Karunya Institute of Technology and Sciences, Coimbatore (2018-2022).

B.Tech Computer Science Engineering.

- CGPA: 6.54.
- St. Joseph's Boys Anglo Indian Higher Secondary School, Coonoor (2016-2018).

Higher secondary Schooling.

- 74.5% in Tamil Nadu HSC Examination.
- St. Joseph's Boys High School, Coonoor (ICSE) (2006-2016).

High Schooli.ng

• 82% in ICSE Board Examination.

About Me

I'm a B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering Graduate with a passion for learning and problem-solving., I am Efficient in transforming software designs and specifications into high-functioning code in the appropriate programming languages. I've worked with various types of projects and have mastered multiple programming languages and coding as well as software testing and debugging.

Professional Experience

DAAI-IDP INTERN AT WIPRO

WIPRO | march 2022- october 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Managed and trained by the company's largest team of software engineers on Data Analytics and Artificial Intelligence (DAAI).
- Gained hands-on project experience and assisted the team on various development protocols and projects.

MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

THE A.I. FOUNDATION | NOV 2020 - DEC 2020

Key responsibilities:

- I learned and practiced Designing and developing machine learning and deep learning systems.
- Assisted the Senior developers in running machine learning tests, and Implementing ML algorithms.

Project

- My project presents an Android Application for the Safety of Women. A single click on this app identifies and shares the harasser through an image and sends a message comprising of the criminal photo and description feeds to the app anonymously without revealing one's identity.
- Other users in the app can view criminal complaint feeds and comment on the corresponding complaint.
- My project was tested and Implemented at my University which brought a sense of safety to Women in my college.

Certifications

- Certification in FastAPI for Data Science sponsored by the Cloud Academy.
- Completed the course and got the certification for Python Programming from the University of MICHIGAN.







REEGUN RUFUS G

Software Engineer



My Contact

reegunrufus07@gmail.com

+916379435342, 9047125185

No 2, LIG Colony, Mount Pleasant, Coonoor, Tamil Nadu, 643102.

Areas of Expertise

- Technical Strengths: Artificial Intelligence, Data Analytics, .Net, AngularJs, JQuery, Linux, JavaScript, HTML, LINUX, Express, and MongoDB.
- Programming Languages: Python, C, C++, Java, C#, Dart, SQL.
- Languages: English (Fluent), Tamil (Native), Hindi (Intermediate).
- Soft Skills: Observation, Decision Making, Communication, Multi-Tasking, Leadership.

Education Background

Karunya Institute of Technology and
Sciences, Coimbatore (2018-2022).

B.Tech Computer Science Engineering.CGPA: 6.54.

St. Joseph's Boys Anglo Indian Higher Secondary School, Coonoor (2016-2018).

Higher secondary Schooling.

- 74.5% in Tamil Nadu HSC Examination.
- St. Joseph's Boys High School, Coonoor (ICSE) (2006-2016).

High Schooling

• 82% in ICSE Board Examination.

About Me

I'm a B.Tech in Computer Science and Engineering Graduate with a passion for learning and problem-solving., I am Efficient in transforming software designs and specifications into high-functioning code in the appropriate programming languages. I've worked with various types of projects and have mastered multiple programming languages and coding as well as software testing and debugging.

Professional Experience

INTERN AT WIPRO

WIPRO I march 2022- november 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Managed and trained by the company's largest team of software engineers on Data Analytics and Artificial Intelligence. I was trained and given hands-on working experience with frontend and back-end technologies such as JavaScript, AngularJs, Python, HTML, JQuery, Mango Db, CSS and Java.
- Gained hands-on project experience and assisted the team with developing protocols and handling customer queries.

MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

THE A.I. FOUNDATION | NOV 2021 - DEC 2021

Key responsibilities:

- I learned and practiced Designing and developing machine learning and deep learning systems.
- Assisted the Senior developers in running machine learning tests, and Implementing ML algorithms.

Project

- My project presents an Android Application for the Safety of Women. A single click on this app identifies and shares the harasser through an image and sends a message comprising of the criminal photo and description feeds to the app anonymously without revealing one's identity.
- Other users in the app can view criminal complaint feeds and comment on the corresponding complaint.
- My project was tested and Implemented at my University which brought a sense of safety to Women in my college.

Certifications

- Certification in FastAPI for Data Science sponsored by the Cloud Academy.
- Completed the course and got the certification for Python Programming from the University of MICHIGAN.







